Inventory of the Grayson Neikirk Kefauver papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Grayson Neikirk Kefauver papers
1900-1955
47003
Kefauver, Grayson Neikirk, 1900-1946.
38 manuscript boxes (15.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, memoranda, speeches and writings, minutes, and printed matter, relating to international educational reconstruction after World War II, and the organization of the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1947.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
August 31, 1900 Born, Middletown, Maryland
1921 BA, University of Arizona
1925 MA, Stanford University
1928 PhD, University of Minnesota
1931-1932 Member of National Survey of Secondary Education, conducted by U.S. Office of Education
1933-1945 Dean of School of Education, Stanford University
1943 Founder and chair, Liaison Committee on International Education, Washington, D.C.
September 1943 Participated in International Education Assembly (IEA), Harpers Ferry, West Virginia
1944 American liaison to the Conference of Allied Ministers of Education (CAME), London
November 1945 Member of U.S. delegation at the Conference for the Establishment of the United Nations Educational and Cultural Organization, London
January 4, 1946 Died, Los Angeles, California
Source: "Grayson Neikirk Kefauver." Dictionary of American Biography. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1974. Gale Biography In Context. Web. 19 Oct. 2012.
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers relate to international educational reconstruction after World War II, and the organization of the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization Correspondence. The papers consist of reports, memoranda, speeches and writings, minutes, and printed matter.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Unesco.; Education.; International education.; Reconstruction (1939-1951); United Nations Preparatory Educational, Scientific and Cultural Commission.
Collection Contents
- Summary of Conferences, New York, 1-9 February 1943 (Folder 1: 1)
- United States. Office of Education, 3 January 1943-9 June 1945 (Folder 1: 2)
- Correspondence on international education, November 1942-January 1944 (Folder 1: 3)
- Stanford Social Education study, Summer 1942 (Folder 1: 4)
- Report on Kefauver's talk in Los Angeles, 3 January 1946 (Folder 1: 5)
- Transcripts, 1900-1955 (Folder 1: 6)
- Stanford University correspondence, March 1943-February 1944 (Folder 1: 7)
- Biographical sketch of Kefauver, undated (Folder 1: 8)
- Kefauver papers and letters, 1946 (Folder 1: 9)
- News clippings, May 1942-December 1945 (Folder 1: 10)
- Ginn and Company, March 1930-February 1950 (Folder 1: 11)
- Liaison Committee, Executive Committee Meeting, 7 September 1944 (Folder 2: 1)
- Liaison Committee, Executive Committee Meeting, 6 February 1945 (Folder 2: 2)
- International Education Assembly (IEA) participants, 12-16 April 1945 (Folder 2: 3)
- Hood College - IEA personal data sheets, 6-9 June 1944 (Folder 2: 4)
- IEA - Executive Committee Meeting, 13 February 1945 (Folder 2: 5)
- The School Executive correspondence, circa 1944-1946 (Folder 2: 6)
- Background book for the United States Delegation to the First General Conference of the United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization (UNESCO): Paris, November 1946 (Folder 2: 7)
- Educational and cultural reconstruction, circa 1945 (Folder 3: 1)
- The Cultural Cooperation Program: 1938-1943, May 1944 (Folder 3: 2)
- Newsletters on international education, Yalta Conference Report, 19 February 1945 (Folder 3: 3)
- Newsletters on international education, May-September 1944 (Folder 3: 4)
- Proposals for an international education foundation, 1943-1944 (Folder 3: 5)
- Memorandum on the reconstruction of education in the Axis countries, circa 1942-1945 (Folder 3: 6)
- National Vocational Guidance Association, 13 December 1944 (Folder 3: 7)
- National Society of College Teachers of Education, circa 1943 (Folder 3: 8)
- Secondary Education Board, 1943-1945 (Folder 3: 9)
- American Federation of Teachers, 1943-1945 (Folder 3: 10)
- American Council on Public Affairs, circa 1943 (Folder 3: 11)
- United States Committee for Intellectual Cooperation, 1942-1946 (Folder 3: 12)
- American Association of School Administration, 1943-1944 (Folder 3: 13)
- National Edcuation Association, 1942-1944 (Folder 3: 14)
- World Federation of Education Associations, 1943-1944 (Folder 3: 15)
- Liaison Committee for International Education, news clippings, correspondence, and proposals, 1942-1945 (Folder 4: 1)
- Informal Conference Coordinating Committee on International Education II, 20 March 1943 (Folder 4: 2)
- Informal Conference Coordinating Committee on International Education III, 20 March 1943 (Folder 4: 3)
- Minutes of meeting on reconstruction of education in Germany, 22 March 1943 (Folder 4: 4)
- Informal Conference Coordination Committee on International Education II, 20 March 1943 (Folder 4: 5)
- Education for War and Peace, Summer 1942 (Folder 4: 6)
- Bibliography documents, 1945-1948 (Folder 4: 7)
- Liaison Committee for International Education, 5 May 1944 (Folder 4: 8)
- American Council of Learned Societies. Joint Meeting of Executive Committee and Advisory Board, 30-31 March 1944 (Folder 4: 9)
- American Council of Learned Societies, 1943-1945 (Folder 4: 10)
- United States. House of Representatives, 1944-1945 (Folder 5: 1)
- National Council for the Social Studies, circa 1943-1944 (Folder 5: 2)
- IEA correspondence, 1943-1945 (Folder 5: 3)
- American Education Fellowship, 1943-1945 (Folder 5: 4)
- Liaison Committee budget, 1943-1945 (Folder 5: 5)
- Receipts, 1944-1945 (Folder 5: 6)
- Liaison Committee meeting, 1945 (Folder 5: 7)
- Liaison Committee mimeographed letters, 15 January 1945 (Folder 5: 8)
- IEA Committee on Constitution, 1944-1945 (Folder 5: 9)
- IEA, Hood College meeting, list of participants, 6-9 June 1944 (Folder 5: 10)
- IEA, Executive committee meeting, 4 November 1944 (Folder 5: 11)
- American Association for Adult Education, 1943-1945 (Folder 5: 12)
- National Commission for the Defense of Democracy Through Education of the National Education Association (NEA), 1943-1944 (Folder 5: 13)
- National Association of Secondary School Principals of the NEA, 1943-1944 (Folder 5: 14)
- Dumbarton Oaks Conference. Meetings called by commission to study the organization of peace, 1944-1945 (Folder 5: 15)
- Foundations, requests for financial aid, circa 1944 (Folder 5: 16)
- National Education Association (NEA), 1944-1945 (Folder 5: 17)
- United States. Senate, 1943-1945 (Folder 5: 18)
- Twentieth Century Fund, 1943-1944 (Folder 5: 19)
- Revision of statement of suggestions concerning the program of the United Nations Organization for Educational and Cultural Reconstruction, 1944-1947 (Folder 5: 20)
- Conference on international education, 14 February 1943 (Folder 5: 21)
- Participants in the Harpers Ferry meeting of the IEA, 13-18 September 1943 (Folder 6: 1)
  Includes agenda, memoranda, personal data sheet, members of IEA Liaison Committee
- IEA New York meeting, personal data sheets, 12-16 April 1945 (Folder 6: 2)
- IEA New York meeting, list of participants, 12-16 April 1945 (Folder 6: 3)
- List of names, 30 April 1943 (Folder 6: 4)
- Columbia Foundation correspondence with Mrs. Elkus, 1944-1945 (Folder 6: 5)
- IEA New York meeting, program, 12-16 April 1945 (Folder 6: 6)
- Liaison Committee, members delegates and addresses, circa 1944 (Folder 6: 7)
- Institute of International Education, 1919-1944 (Folder 6: 8)
- American Education Research Association, 1943-1944 (Folder 6: 9)
- IEA New York Meeting, Foreign Delegates, invitations and replies, 12-16 April 1945 (Folder 6: 10)
- Liaison Committee Meeting speakers, 5 May 1944 (Folder 6: 11)
  Includes Dr. Studenbaker, Congressman Fullbright, and Dean Thompson
- American Council of Education, Institute of Pacific Relations, Inc., 1943-1944 (Folder 7: 1)
- American Association of Teachers and Colleges, 1943-1944 (Folder 7: 2)
- American Association of University Women, 1942-1945 (Folder 7: 3)
  Includes copies of "General Director's Letter"
- Liaison Committee (Folder 7)
  - Mimeographed letter to members of the Liaison Committee, 29 January 1946 (Folder 7: 4)
  - Letter to Senators, 6 February 1946 (Folder 7: 5)
  - Letter to Representatives on Unesco, 6 February 1946 (Folder 7: 6)
  - Mimeographed letter to members of the liaison committee, 7 December 1945 (Folder 7: 7)
  - Liaison Committee for International Education, 5 May 1944 (Folder 7: 8)
- American Library Association, 1943-1945 (Folder 7: 9)
- Liaison Committee meeting, 3 August 1945 (Folder 7: 10)
- Education for International Security letters and replies from embassies, 1943-1945 (Folder 7: 11)
- Education for International Security replies from government officials, circa 1943 (Folder 8: 1)
- Workers Education Bureau, 1944-1945 (Folder 8: 2)
- Committee on International Relations of the National Education Association, 1943-1944 (Folder "8: 3)
- Liaison Committee meeting, "Report of Chairman G. N. Kefauver,", 31 January-1 February 1944 (Folder 8: 4)
- Liaison Committee, letter to Secretary of State Stettinius, 28 February 1945 (Folder 8: 5)
- Liaison Committee, miscellaneous memoranda, 1943-1944 (Folder 8: 6)
- Liaison Committee membership, invitations issued and applications received, 1944-1945 (Folder 8: 7)
- Liaison Committee, annual report, 1 March 1944-28 February 1945 (Folder 8: 8)
- Liaison Committee meeting, San Francisco, 28 April 1945 (Folder 8: 9)
- San Francisco conference, April-May 1945 (Folder 8: 10)
- Educational Policies Commission, 1943-1945 (Folder 9: 1)
- American Red Cross, circa 1945 (Folder 9: 2)
- Association of American Colleges, 1943-1944 (Folder 9: 3)
- Association of American Universities, 1943-1944 (Folder 9: 4)
- Assocation of Colleges and Secondary Schools for Negroes, 1943-1944 (Folder 9: 5)
- Application for Childhood Education, 1944-1945 (Folder 9: 6)
- Board of Tellers, 27 January 1945 (Folder 9: 7)
- Commission to Study the Organizations of Peace, 1943-1944 (Folder 9: 8)
- U.S. Chamber of Commerce, 1944 (Folder 9: 9)
- Commission on Post-War Planning of the American Federation of Teachers, 1943-1944 (Folder 9: 10)
- Commision on Trends in Eduction of the Modern Language Association, 1943-1944 (Folder 9: 11)
- Committee on International Education and Cultural Relations of the American Council on Education, May 1944 (Folder 9: 12)
- Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, correspondence with Malcom Davis, February 1943-March 1945 (Folder 9: 13)
- Office of the Coordinator of Inter-Amercan Affairs, 1943-1945 (Folder 9: 14)
- Philadelphia Conference on Providing Educational Opportunites for Students from War-Torn Countries, 1 March 1944 (Folder 9: 15)
- Department of Adult Education of the National Education Association, 1943-1945 (Folder 9: 16)
- United States Committee on Educational Reconstruction, 1943-1944 (Folder 9: 17)
- Congressional Action of an International Office of Education Resolution, H215 and S122, May 1945 (Folder 9: 18)
- Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America, 18 March 1944 (Folder 10: 1)
- Dumbarton Oaks Conference, 1944-1945 (Folder 10: 2)
- Educational Press Association of America, August-October 1944 (Folder 10: 3)
- Mailing lists of Harpers Ferry conference report, 1943-1944 (Folder 10: 4)
- IEA correspondence, 1944 (Folder 10: 5)
- IEA correspondence with Dr. Edgar J. Fisher, 1944-1945 (Folder 10: 6)
- Hood College memoranda, 16 June 1944 (Folder 10: 7)
- IEA, original materials for "Education in the United Nations,", 24 July 1944 (Folder 10: 8)
- Edward Hazen Foundation, Inc., 1943-1944 (Folder 10: 9)
- IEA preliminary drafts of "Education for a Free Society,", circa 1944 (Folder 10: 10)
- IEA meeting, New York City, correspondence, 12-16 April 1945 (Folder 10: 11)
- Institute for the Advancement of Visual Education and Vocational Training, 1943-1944 (Folder 11: 1)
- International Auxiliary Language Association, 1945 (Folder 11: 2)
- International Council of Religious Education, 1943-1945 (Folder 11: 3)
- Waldo Leland, Organization of International Educational Relations, Conference on Inernational Education, 21 March 1943 (Folder 11: 4)
- Modern Language Association, 1943-1945 (Folder 11: 5)
- The Nation Associates correspondence with Freda Kirchwey, circa 1944 (Folder 11: 6)
- Department of Supervision and Curriculum Development of the National Education Association, 1943-1944 (Folder 11: 7)
- Department of Elementary School Principles of the National Education Association, April 1943-1944 (Folder 11: 8)
- Commission on Resources and Education of the National Education Association and the Progressive Education Association, 1943-1944 (Folder 11: 9)
- United Nations Information Office, 1943-1944 (Folder 11: 10)
- Washington Letter on the United Nations: Livingston Hartley, circa 1945 (Folder 11: 11)
- World Education Service Council, 1944-1945 (Folder 11: 12)
- OWI, 1943-1945 (Folder 11: 13)
- UNESCO, general clippings, undated (Folder 11: 14)
- Mexico City, Second general conference, 1947 (Folder 11: 15)
- San Francisco Pacific Region Conference clippings, 1948 (Folder 11: 16)
- Kefauver papers and letters, circa 1947 (Folder 11: 17)
- Paris First General Conference, 1946 (Folder 11: 18)
- Denver Conference press clippings, 15-17 May 1947 (Folder 11: 19)
- Institute of International Education, 1944-1946 (Folder 11: 20)
- American Council on Education, circa 1945 (Folder 12: 1)
- Edgar J. Fisher correspondence regarding Liaison Committee and International Education Assembly, 1943-1944 (Folder 12: 2)
- Unesco broadcasts, 1946 (Folder 12: 3)
- Fannie Fern Andrews, undated (Folder 12: 4)
- "The Nation: Unesco Gets to Work" by A. G. Mezerik, 30 November 1946 (Folder 12: 5)
- Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America, 1945-1946 (Folder 12: 6)
- United States Committee on Educational Reconstruction, 1940-1941 (Folder 12: 7)
- Articles on Unesco by Howard E. Wilson, 1946-1947 (Folder 12: 8)
- World Peace Foundation, 1946-1947 (Folder 12 :9)
- Church Peace Union, 1947 (Folder 12 :10)
- U.S. Committee on Edcuational Reconstruction from R. Schairer, 1941-1943 (Folder 12: 11)
- NEA Committee on International Relations, 1944 (Folder 12: 12)
- Waldo G. Leland, 1940-1946 (Folder 12: 13)
- Waldo G.Leland lecture, Stanford University, 25 July 1947 (Folder 12: 14)
- "Charts: The United Nations, State Presentations,", undated (Folder 12: 15)
- Miscellaneous, 1946 (Folder 12: 16)
  Includes report of the U.S. Education Mission to Japan
- Ben M. Cherrington, 1946 (Folder 12: 17)
  "All Things are Ready if Our Minds Be So"(2 copies); "Foreigners No Longer: Special Broadcasts in Observance of UNESCO Month;" "America's Future Cultural Relations" (2 copies)"
- "The School Executive Understanding Through Education,", October 1946 (Folder 12: 18)
- H.R. 4368 and H.R. 4982. Hearings before the Committee on Foreign Affairs House of Representatives, 1945-1946 (Folder 12: 19)
- H.R. 3342. The United States Information and Educational Exchange Act of 1947 (Folder 12: 20)
- H.R. 215. International Office of Education, 1945 (Folder 12: 21)
- H.J. Res. 305. "Membership and Participation by the United States in the United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization,", 1946 (Folder 12: 22)
- Congressional Records of 79th and 80th Congresses, undated (Folder 12: 23)
- International educational reconstruction, 1946-1948 (Folder 13: 1)
- John W. Studebaker Inter-American Education, undated (Folder 13: 2)
- The United Nations, circa 1946 (Folder 13: 3)
  "Charter of the United Nations," "How Will the United Nations Work?" and "Report of U.S. Delegation to First Session of the General Assembly of the United Nations, London"
- S. 1440 and S. 1636, March 1946 (Folder 13: 4)
- H.R. 2083 (Copyrights), 21 April 1943 (Folder 13: 5)
- American Association of University Women (McHale), Summer 1945 (Folder 13: 6)
- Interdepartmental Committee on Cultural and Scientific Cooperation, 1942-1946 (Folder 13: 7)
- San Francisco Conference, 1945 (Folder 13: 8)
- Dumbarton Oaks Conference, October 1944 (Folder 13: 9)
- Liaison Committee for International Education, 1944-1947 (Folder 13: 10)
- Unesco miscellany, 1946 (Folder 14: 1)
- Carr (Folder 14)
  - Letters from London, circa 1945 (Folder 14: 2)
  - Letters from San Francisco, circa 1945 (Folder 14: 3)
  - Letters from Paris, circa 1946 (Folder 14: 4)
- Department of State bulletins, circa 1946 (Folder 14: 5)
- Office of International Information and Cultural Affairs, 9 February 1947 (Folder 14: 6)
- London Conference, 1946 (Folder 14: 7)
- Reports of consultants, 1946 (Folder 14: 8)
- Carr speeches, undated (Folder 14: 9)
- "Increasing Amount of Data on Foreign Affairs Issued by State Department," by John S. Dickey, 7 September 1944 (Folder 14: 10)
- "U.S. Department of State. Office of Public Affairs and Unesco: A Provisional Program,", October 1946 (Folder 14: 11)
- U.S. Department of State. Unesco relations staff, circa 1947 (Folder 14: 12)
- Unesco reports, circa 1947 (Folder 14: 13)
- Department of State publications, circa 1946 (Folder 14: 14)
- Preparatory Commission, circa 1946 (Folder 15: 1)
- Regional Conference on the Humanities, Estes Park, Colorado, June 1946 (Folder 15: 2)
- Carl H. Milam, American Library Association, November 1946 (Folder 15: 3)
  Includes letter to Kefauver and letters from Paris
- American Federation of Labor, 1946 (Folder 15: 4)
- First General Conference, Paris, 1946 (Folder 15: 5)
- Unesco Paris conference, November 1946 (Folder 15: 6)
- "Conference on Science, Philosophy, and Religion,", circa 1944 (Folder 16: 1)
- Take to Washington, circa 1943 (Folder 16: 2)
- Education in Germany, 1943-1955 (Folder 16: 3)
- "Basic Differences in American and National Socialist Education,", undated (Folder 16: 4)
- Memorandum on reconstruction of education in the Axis countries, December 1942 (Folder 16: 5)
- International Education Organization, circa 1943 (Folder 16: 6)
- Bertrand Russell: Proposals for an International University, July 1942 (Folder 16: 7)
- Kefauver World Federation, circa 1942 (Folder 16: 8)
- USSR education, undated (Folder 16: 9)
- Danish education, 2 May 1939 (Folder 16: 10)
- "Education: An Important Factor in Achieving an Enduring Peace,", circa 1943 (Folder 16: 11)
- Newspaper clippings, circa 1943 (Folder 16: 12)
- Proposal for the establisment of an International Commission on Education, circa 1942 (Folder 16: 13)
- Miscellaneous manuscripts, circa 1943 (Folder 17: 1)
- Atomic control, circa 1945 (Folder 17: 2)
- Education and the war, circa 1942 (Folder 17: 3)
- Liaison Committee conferences, circa 1945 (Folder 17: 4)
- National Survey of Student Engagement (NSSE), 1942-1944 (Folder 17: 5)
- Kefauver: General agreement on international action in education, July 1943 (Folder 17: 6)
- Kefauver: speeches, circa 1942 (Folder 17: 7)
- First Session of the General Conference of Unesco, Paris, 19 November-10 December 1946 (Folder 18: 1)
- "Post-War Education, Peace Aims, Misc.,", 1942-1943 (Folder 18: 2)
- Miscellaneous articles filed by author, 1942-1943 (Folder 18: 3)
- Kefauver: Peace Aims Call for International Action in Education, undated (Folder 18: 4)
- Educational Reconstruction for the Four Central and Eastern European Nations, March 1943 (Folder 18: 5)
- Progressive Education Association (PEA) and Post-War materials, circa 1941 (Folder 18: 6)
- Foundations, circa 1943 (Folder 18: 7)
- Section meetings, 25 March 1947 (Folder 19: 1)
- General sessions, March 1947 (Folder 19: 2)
- Representatives of organizations attending the Philadelphia conference, March 1947 (Folder 19: 3)
- Transcripts and interviews, 1940-1943 (Folder 19: 4)
- Philadelphia conference summary program, 24-26 March 1947 (Folder 19: 5)
- President Truman's message to first national conference and message from Julian Huxley, 24-26 March 1947 (Folder 19: 6)
- Press releases, 24-26 March 1947 (Folder 19: 7)
- Progress report on Unesco and its relation to the national commission, 24-26 March 1947 (Folder 19: 8)
- "Selected Documents of U.S. National Commissions, First Meeting,", September 1946 (Folder "19: 9)
- Mountain Plains Regular Conference, Denver, Colorado (Folder 19)
  - "Guide: National Conference on Unesco, Philadelphia,", 24-26 March 1947 (Folder 19: 10)
  - Section meetings: summary reports, 24-26 March 1947 (Folder 19: 11)
  - "Invitation, Pre Registration, Registration, etc.,", 15-17 May 1947 (Folder 20: 1)
  - Subject forums, 15-17 May 1947 (Folder 20: 2)
  - Mass media, 15-17 May 1947 (Folder 20: 3)
  - Conference reports from organizational sections, 15-17 May 1947 (Folder 20: 4)
  - Organizational section meetings, 15-17 May 1947 (Folder 20: 5)
  - Educational reconstruction, 15-17 May 1947 (Folder 20: 6)
  - Plenary speeches, 15-17 May 1947 (Folder 20: 7)
  - Handbook of the United States National Commission for the United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization, 15-17 May 1947 (Folder 20: 8)
  - Press releases, 15-17 May 1947 (Folder 21: 1)
  - Guide and program, 15-17 May 1947 (Folder 21: 2)
  - Directory, 15-17 May 1947 (Folder 21: 3)
  - Working papers, 15-17 May 1947 (Folder 21: 4)
  - Report on Mountain Plains Regional Conference, 15-17 May 1947 (Folder 21: 5)
- Unesco Regional Conference, San Francisco, California, 13-15 May 1948 (Folder 21)
  - Central Planning Committee (Folder 21: 6)
  - "Unesco and Community Action" by Louis Wasserman (Folder 21: 7)
  - Press releases (Folder 21: 8)
  - Roster of delegates (Folder 21: 9)
  - Group meetings (Folder 22:)
    - Cultural interchange (Folder 22: 1)
    - Human and social relations (Folder 22: 2)
  - Plenary speeches (Folder 22: 3)
  - "Unesco and You," U.S. Department of State, Publication 2904, IOC Series IV (Folder 22: 4)
  - Progress reports (1-9), conference planning documents (Folder 22: 5)
  - Unesco Pacific Regional Conference Guides (Folder 22: 6)
  - Tentative programs (Folder 22: 7)
  - Tentative pattern, section meetings (Folder 22: 8)
  - Wallace Stegner report (Folder 22: 9)
  - Section meeting reports (Folder 22: 10)
  - Luncheon meetings (Folder 22: 11)
  - Registration and reservations (Folder 22: 12)
  - Suggestions for group leaders (Folder 22: 13)
  - Group meetings (Folder 22:)
    - Education (Folder 22: 14)
    - Communication (Folder 22: 15)
    - Natural Sciences (Folder 22: 16)
  - General information (Folder 22: 17)
  - Order of the day (Folder 22: 18)
  - Index and order list of materials relating to Unesco (Folder 22: 19)
  - Background materials for Pacific Regional Conference (Folder 22: 20)
- IEA New York meeting, general correspondence, 12-16 April 1945 (Folder 22: 21)
- Liaison Committee (Folder 23:)
  - Minutes of Hood College meeting, 5-9 June 1944 (Folder 23: 1)
  - Meeting, 20-22 May 1943 (Folder 23: 2)